<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Butler</title>
    <link>https://butler.ptarmiganlabs.com/docs/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Butler</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://butler.ptarmiganlabs.com/docs/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Butler</title>
      <link>https://butler.ptarmiganlabs.com/docs/about/butler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://butler.ptarmiganlabs.com/docs/about/butler/</guid>
      <description>The Butler project is all about adding useful features to the client-managed version of Qlik Sense, also known as Qlik Sense Enterprise on Windows, QSEoW.&#xA;Some of the features can be used from Sense load scripts, other features provide integration with 3rd party systems.&#xA;Most of Butler&amp;rsquo;s features try to make daily life for a Qlik Sense administrator a bit easier.&#xA;The goal is to integrate battle-proven concepts and best-of-breed open-source tools into Butler and thus make them available to developers of Sense apps or those responsible for running Sense clusters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Butler family</title>
      <link>https://butler.ptarmiganlabs.com/docs/about/butler-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://butler.ptarmiganlabs.com/docs/about/butler-family/</guid>
      <description>Butler started out with a very specific need to start Sense reloads from outside systems.&#xA;Over the years a few projects (for example Butler SOS, which simplifies day 2 operations ([1], [2]) have spun off from the original Butler project, and still other projects have been created from scratch to solve specific challenges around developing Sense apps and running Qlik Sense server environments.&#xA;All members of the Butler family are available on Ptarmigan Labs&amp;rsquo; GitHub page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Versions</title>
      <link>https://butler.ptarmiganlabs.com/docs/about/versioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://butler.ptarmiganlabs.com/docs/about/versioning/</guid>
      <description>In the spirit of not copying information to several places, the version history is kept as annotations of each release on the GitHub release page.&#xA;Version numbers include up to 3 levels, for example version 4.6.2 (which is a fictitious version):&#xA;4 is the major version. It is increased when Butler has added major new features, or in other ways changed in major ways. If following this principle, breaking changes should always result in a bumped major version.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contribution guidelines</title>
      <link>https://butler.ptarmiganlabs.com/docs/about/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://butler.ptarmiganlabs.com/docs/about/contributing/</guid>
      <description>Butler is an open source project, using the MIT license.&#xA;This means that all source code, documentation etc is available as-is, at no cost.&#xA;It however also means that anyone interested can - and is encouraged to - contribute to the project!&#xA;Butler is developed in Node.js, with support from various NPM modules.&#xA;We use Hugo to format and generate this documentation site, the Docsy theme for styling and site structure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Telemetry</title>
      <link>https://butler.ptarmiganlabs.com/docs/about/telemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://butler.ptarmiganlabs.com/docs/about/telemetry/</guid>
      <description>Sharing telemetry data from Butler is optional.&#xA;You can use all Butler features without sharing telemetry data.&#xA;That said, if you find the Butler tool useful you are strongly encouraged to leave Butler&amp;rsquo;s telemetry feature turned on.&#xA;Having access to this data greatly helps the Butler developers when they design new features, fix bugs etc.&#xA;The Butler developers care about you - sharing telemetry data is your way of showing you care about them.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
